If you've ever had to manage a live conference —
keeping track of which speaker is on stage,
whether they're running late, what the AV team is doing,
what the interpreter room needs —
you know how chaotic it can get.
CueDeck is a realtime production console built specifically for live events.
One URL, every role, everything synced instantly.
Let me show you what it can do.
CueDeck lives entirely in the browser —
no app to install, no setup wizard that takes three hours.
You sign in, pick your event, and you're in.
What you see here is the Production Console —
this is the director view.
On the left you've got a live session list for today's event.
Each card shows the session title,
the room, the speaker, the planned time,
and the current status.
On the right is the context panel —
this is where you take action.
Go live, put a session on hold,
call the speaker to stage, apply a delay.
Every action is a single click,
and it propagates to every connected device in under a second.
CueDeck has six roles, each with exactly the right level
of access for the job.
The Director has full control —
they see everything, do everything.
Stage managers can transition sessions and mark speaker arrivals.
AV can see what's live and what's coming.
Interpretation rooms get a dedicated view with the session queue.
Registration sees who's next on stage.
And the Signage role manages the digital displays around the venue.
Everyone gets the right information at the right time —
no more group chats, no more walkie-talkie chaos.
Over the next episodes we're going to walk through every
feature — live, in a real event.
We'll create an event from scratch,
add sessions, run them through the full state machine —
READY, LIVE, HOLD, ENDED.
You'll see the delay cascade, the broadcast bar,
the digital signage system with ten display modes,
the AI agents that help when
things go sideways, the stage confidence monitor,
the stage timer, and a lot more.
By the end of this series you'll be able to
run your first production event on CueDeck solo.
CueDeck is free to try — no credit card needed.
Head to app.cuedeck.io, create your account,
and follow along with the next episode where
we'll set up our first event together.
If you've got questions drop them in the comments.
I'll see you in episode two.