In episode one we got a quick tour of CueDeck.
Now let's actually build something.
In the next few minutes I'm going to create a
full conference event, add sessions, and
have it ready to run live.
This is 'Tech Summit 2026' —
a single-day tech conference in London.
Let's go.
You land here.
Enter your email and password, hit sign in.
CueDeck uses Supabase Auth under the hood —
your credentials are secure and the session persists across tabs.
First time here?
Click 'Create Account', enter the invite code your director gave
you, or start a free trial.
We'll cover the invite flow in episode seven.
For a brand new account, the setup wizard kicks in.
Four steps — create your event,
add a session, invite your team,
set up a display.
Let's follow it.
Step one: create the event.
Name: Tech Summit 2026.
Date: April 15th.
Timezone: Europe London.
Event runs 9am to 6pm.
Venue: Grand Convention Centre London.
Hit Save.
Now we have an event with no sessions.
Let's add them.
Click the plus button.
Each session has a title, a type —
keynote, panel, workshop, break, sponsor —
a room name, a speaker, their company,
planned start and end times, and
a sort order to control the running order.
I'll also tick 'Recording' and 'Streaming' for the keynote —
these flags appear on every role's view so the AV
team knows what to prep.
Save.
There it is — first session,
status PLANNED, showing in the list.
I'll add a few more —
a panel and a lunch break.
Notice the lunch break is type 'break' so it renders
with a different visual treatment in the list.
In a real event you'd add all ten or
twenty sessions up front.
You can also duplicate sessions from a previous event —
there's a seed-from option in the event modal that
copies the full schedule.
Need to reorder?
Click the up/down arrows on any session card,
or edit the sort_order directly.
The list re-sorts instantly.
To edit a session — click anywhere on the card.
The modal comes back pre-filled.
Change the speaker, adjust the time, tick or untick flags.
Save.
Once you have a full programme,
the filter bar keeps you sane.
Type a speaker name — matching sessions surface immediately.
Click a room chip to see just that room's schedule.
Filter by status to find everything that's still PLANNED.
These filters are local — they don't affect what anyone else sees.
That's it — event created, sessions in, programme structured.
In the next episode we'll go live for the first
time and walk through the full session state machine —
READY, CALLING, LIVE, HOLD, ENDED.
Subscribe so you don't miss it.
See you in episode three.