Your event is set up.
Sessions are in.
It's showtime.
In this episode I'm going to walk you through the
entire session lifecycle — from PLANNED,
through READY, CALLING, LIVE, HOLD, and ENDED.
This is the core of CueDeck,
and once you understand how the state machine works,
running a complex event becomes straightforward.
Every session in CueDeck lives in one of eight states:
PLANNED — it's on the programme,
nothing has happened yet.
READY — the room is set up,
we're expecting the speaker.
CALLING — the speaker is being called to stage.
LIVE — on stage right now.
HOLD — live but paused, speaker is waiting.
OVERRUN — the session went past its scheduled end time.
ENDED — finished.
CANCELLED — removed from the running order.
Transitions flow in one direction.
You can't accidentally move a session backwards through the machine.
And every state change is timestamped and logged.
It's 9:15 — fifteen minutes before the keynote.
The room is set up.
Let's move Sarah's session to READY.
Click the session to select it.
The context panel shows 'Set Ready'.
Click it.
The card flips to a green READY badge.
Every connected device — the stage manager's phone,
the AV laptop, the display monitors —
updates in under a second.
9:25.
Time to call Sarah to stage.
Click CALLING.
The card goes amber — every stage manager knows to
go find the speaker.
The broadcast bar can send a message to the whole
crew at the same time —
we'll cover that in episode five.
Sarah's on stage.
It's 9:30.
Hit GO LIVE.
The session card turns bright green,
the status changes to LIVE, and
the actual_start timestamp is recorded.
The clock starts.
If you have digital displays or
a stage confidence monitor set up —
we'll build those in episodes eight and
nine — they all flip to show this session live.
Sometimes you need to pause mid-session.
Fire alarm, technical issue, speaker needs water.
Hit HOLD.
The session freezes.
The stage timer freezes.
Everyone on every device sees the HOLD state.
When you're ready to resume, click LIVE again —
the session continues from where it was,
timer picks back up.
Sarah went 3 minutes over on her demo.
We need to adjust the rest of the programme.
The nudge buttons add or subtract a minute from the
current session's end time.
The delay cascade automatically shifts every subsequent PLANNED session forward.
You can see the knock-on effect ripple down the session list in realtime.
We'll go deep on delay management in episode six.
Session done.
Click END SESSION.
Status flips to ENDED with a green check.
Actual end time is recorded.
The time variance — how far over or
under planned — is calculated and stored.
You'll see all of this in the post-event report.
On the next session — the panel —
you can mark speakers as arrived before the session is even called.
The stage manager ticks 'Speaker Arrived' on each panellist as
they check in backstage.
Directors can see at a glance whether all speakers are present.
This feeds into the pre-cue AI agent too —
but that's episode ten.
That's the full session lifecycle.
PLANNED → READY → CALLING → LIVE → ENDED,
with HOLD and delay nudges along the way.
In the next episode we'll look at roles —
how to invite your team and
what each role can see and do.
See you in episode four.