A live event is a team sport.
Director, stage managers, AV engineers, interpreters,
registration desk — everyone needs the right information,
and only the right information.
CueDeck handles this with six distinct roles,
each with a tailored view and
a specific set of permissions.
The Director sees everything.
Full session list, full context panel,
all action buttons — Set Ready,
Go Live, Hold, End, nudge, delay cascade, signage, broadcast.
This is the person running the show.
Stage Managers get the session list with status badges and
the ability to mark speaker arrivals.
They can transition sessions — Set Ready,
Call Speaker, Go Live.
They don't see financials or settings.
AV engineers see what's LIVE right now,
what's coming next, and the recording/streaming flags on each session.
They don't need the full programme —
just what's relevant to their setup.
Interpretation booths get a clean queue view —
current session, next session, language flags.
If a session has interpretation enabled, it shows here.
No clutter.
Registration desk sees who's on stage,
what's next, and can check in arrivals.
Simple, focused.
Signage operators manage the digital display panel —
adding and configuring screens, changing modes, uploading sponsor logos.
They don't touch sessions at all.
To add someone to your event,
go to the team panel.
Click Invite Operator.
Enter their email address.
Choose their role.
Hit Send Invite.
They get an email with a magic link.
They click it, set their password if they're new,
and they're in — automatically scoped to your event with
the role you assigned.
The invite is tied to you as the event director.
If they're already a CueDeck user they just get access
to your event instantly.
Not sure what a role can do?
Hit the question mark in the header, then Quick Reference.
You'll see a full table of every state transition and
which roles can trigger it.
Directors get everything.
Stage managers get transitions.
AV and Interp are read-only for sessions.
This is your field reference during production.
Six roles, zero confusion.
Everyone sees what they need, nothing they don't.
In the next episode we'll look at the broadcast bar
— how you send real-time messages to every connected device on your team.
Subscribe and I'll see you in episode five.