Group chats during a live event are noise.
By the time someone reads a message and
replies, the moment has passed.
CueDeck's broadcast bar solves this —
one message, every connected device, zero round-trips.
The broadcast bar sits at the top of the console.
Directors type a message, hit send,
and it appears immediately across all connected devices —
every stage manager, every AV engineer,
every interpretation booth — as a coloured overlay they can't miss.
Messages dismiss when each person taps them.
The director can see who's cleared it.
It's not a chat — it's a command.
Let's send one.
Click the broadcast bar.
Type your message — 'Delay 5 minutes — hold all transitions'.
There's a character counter.
Keep it short and punchy —
this is a live environment.
Hit Send.
Watch.
Boom.
Every connected role sees it instantly.
The banner sits at the top of their view until they dismiss it.
They can't accidentally miss it scrolling past.
For common situations you'll use over and
over, CueDeck has broadcast presets.
One click — no typing needed.
'HOLD — Do not proceed.' Great for when
you need everything to pause right now.
'Speakers to stage immediately.' Self-explanatory.
'Running 5 minutes late — adjust your clocks.' The director
can customise these presets for each event in advance.
We'll show that in the signage episode.
Each person dismisses the message on their own device.
The director doesn't need to clear it globally.
Local dismiss means everyone works at their own pace once
they've acknowledged the instruction.
The broadcast stays visible until dismissed — it doesn't auto-fade.
Clear, instant, impossible to miss.
That's the broadcast bar.
Next episode — delay management.
What happens when a session runs long and
you need to cascade a delay through the rest of
the programme without losing your mind.
See you in episode six.