Every live event production team knows the feeling.
The keynote runs long.
Or a panel goes fifteen minutes over.
Suddenly your entire afternoon programme is out of sync —
and you're the only person who knows it.
In this episode we're going to look at one of
CueDeck's most useful features: the delay cascade.
It's how you absorb overruns without losing control of your
programme, and it takes about three seconds to use.
Before we hit any buttons, let's understand the two numbers
CueDeck tracks behind the scenes.
Every session in the database has a `planned_start` and
a `planned_end` — those are the times your programme was originally designed around.
They never change.
Think of them as your baseline.
When you apply a delay, CueDeck writes to a separate
pair of fields: `scheduled_start` and `scheduled_end`.
These are the working times —
the live reality of your programme right now.
On top of that, each session carries two delay counters.
`delay_minutes` is the delay applied directly to this specific session
— it's what caused the original ripple.
`cumulative_delay` is the total shift this session has accumulated,
which can be larger if multiple delays have been applied upstream.
You can see the cumulative delay on every affected session
card — that amber tag showing plus-something-minutes.
That number tells you how far behind the original programme
this session is sitting right now.
This session, for example, is running ten minutes behind its planned start.
The director applied a delay upstream,
and it cascaded down to here automatically.
Let me show you how that works.
In the director view, whenever a session is READY,
CALLING, or LIVE, you'll see a row of amber buttons
labeled +MIN — five, ten, and fifteen.
These are your delay controls.
Let's say the current session was scheduled to end at
two-fifteen, but it's two-twenty and the speaker is still going.
I'll hit plus-five.
Watch the session list.
Every session below this one that
is in a PLANNED state just shifted forward five minutes.
Their `scheduled_start` and `scheduled_end` both moved.
The amber plus-five tag appeared on each of them.
And up at the top of the session list,
the delay strip appeared — it tells us the programme
is now running plus-five minutes, with three sessions affected.
The director console doesn't reload, it doesn't ask for a confirmation dialog.
The cascade happens client-side first for instant feedback,
and then writes to the database in the background for
all other connected devices.
But here's the scenario most multi-day conferences run into:
you have fixed-time slots that cannot move.
The lunch break at one o'clock.
The opening ceremony.
The gala dinner at seven.
Those sessions need to hold their ground no matter what
happens in the morning.
That's what anchor sessions are for.
When you tick the Anchor checkbox on a session in
the edit modal, you're telling CueDeck:
stop the cascade here.
Watch what happens when I apply a delay with an
anchor session in the list.
The sessions between the live one and
the lunch break all shifted.
But the lunch break itself didn't move.
Neither did anything after it.
The anchor absorbed the delay —
it acts as a firewall for your fixed-time commitments.
And in the delay strip at the top,
you'll see the anchor is called out by name:
it tells you the cascade stopped at 'Lunch Break, 13:00'.
That's your reminder that your afternoon is still on schedule.
There's a second set of controls that's specifically for the
session that's currently LIVE: the nudge buttons.
These are different from the delay cascade.
Nudge only affects the session that's running right now —
it moves its end time by one minute without cascading anything downstream.
It's for micro-corrections.
If a speaker wraps up a minute early and
you want to give the AV team a slightly longer
transition window, hit minus-one.
If they need just one more minute to finish their thought, hit plus-one.
The timer in the live card updates immediately,
and so does the stage timer display if you have one connected.
Small adjustments, no drama.
Now let's say the session that
was running late actually ended on time after all —
or maybe you applied a delay by accident,
or the event got back on track.
You want to wipe the slate clean and
go back to the original programme.
Hit Reset delays in the orange strip.
CueDeck asks for a single confirmation tap —
it changed to 'Confirm reset?' —
because this is destructive.
Once I confirm, every session's scheduled times go back to their planned originals.
Every delay tag disappears.
The delay strip goes away.
The programme is clean again.
Under the hood, CueDeck is writing `scheduled_start` and
`scheduled_end` back to `planned_start` and `planned_end` for every affected session,
and zeroing out both delay counters.
A few things worth knowing when
you're running a multi-room event.
First: the cascade only touches sessions in the same programme
sequence as the session you delayed.
It works through sort order, not through room assignment.
So if Hall A is running late and
you delay Hall A's keynote, sessions in Hall B are not touched.
You'd apply a delay to Hall B separately if needed.
Second: the cascade stops at ENDED and
CANCELLED sessions too — it skips them.
So if a session was cancelled earlier in the day,
it won't interfere with the propagation logic.
Third: for events with a hard parallel track —
say, a workshop that always runs from two to three
regardless of the plenary room —
make the first session of that track an anchor.
That way no director action on the main stage can
accidentally push your workshop slots around.
And finally: the delay strip is visible to all roles
in director view, not just the person who applied the delay.
So your whole team can see at a glance that
the programme is running plus-ten and plan accordingly.
The delay cascade is one of those features that
sounds complicated until you've used it once,
and then you wonder how you ever ran a live event without it.
One click shifts your entire programme.
Anchor sessions protect your fixed times.
Nudge gives you per-minute surgical control on the running session.
And reset brings everything back to plan in two taps.
In the next episode we're moving into the digital signage
system — how to set up displays around your venue
and get them all pulling live data from CueDeck.
See you there.