When you're running a live event as a director,
your eyes are everywhere.
You're watching the session list, the broadcast bar,
the delay strip, the operator presence indicators.
Somewhere in the middle of that,
you also need to know what's actually happening on stage
at this exact moment — without having to hunt for the session card.
That's what the Stage Confidence Monitor is for.
One click and your entire screen becomes a single,
giant, impossible-to-miss display of the current session.
Let me show you.
In the context panel on the right side of the
director console — the same panel that
shows your quick action buttons —
scroll down to the Monitor section.
You'll see a button labeled 'Stage Monitor' with a little screen icon.
Click it.
The overlay fills the entire screen.
This is not a new browser window or
a new tab — it's a fixed overlay that
sits on top of the production console at z-index nine thousand.
Your console is still running underneath,
all your realtime subscriptions are still live,
you haven't navigated away from anything.
At the top: the live session status in red —
a pulsing dot and the words 'YOU ARE LIVE'.
In the centre: the session title in massive type —
responsive, so it scales with your screen size.
Up to eighty pixels on a large display.
Below that, the speaker's name.
Below that: the timer.
A large monospaced countdown showing minutes and
seconds remaining — the exact same clock that
drives the timer cards in the session list,
synced to the server via CueDeck's clock offset mechanism.
At the bottom of the centre section: the next session.
Title, speaker, room, scheduled start time —
everything the director needs to think one step ahead.
And in a thin footer bar at the very bottom:
the live clock on the right,
the event name on the left.
The timer on the stage monitor uses the same three-colour
scheme you'll see everywhere in CueDeck.
Green: the session has more than five minutes remaining.
You're in good shape.
The label below the timer says 'REMAINING'.
Amber: under five minutes left.
The timer colour shifts to amber and
the label changes to 'WRAPPING UP'.
This is your nudge to start thinking about the transition.
Red: under two minutes.
The label becomes 'ENDING NOW'.
Time to get ready to call the next session to stage.
If the session goes into OVERRUN —
past its scheduled end time —
the timer flips to show a positive number and
the label changes to 'OVERTIME'.
The timer counts upward, telling you exactly how far over time you are.
These thresholds are the same five-minute and
two-minute marks used in the session cards and
the stage timer display mode —
the whole system speaks the same visual language.
In practice, the Stage Confidence Monitor is for a very
specific moment: when the director needs to be physically watching
something else — the stage door,
the operator feed, a conversation with the venue manager —
but still needs peripheral awareness of the current session state.
You pop it open on a secondary monitor or
a dedicated screen, and you never have to dig through
the session list to answer 'how much time does the
current speaker have left'.
It's right there, full screen, two metres away.
It also syncs immediately with state changes.
The moment you or another director transitions the session —
ENDED, HOLD, OVERRUN — the stage monitor updates.
No delay, no refresh.
The live session switches, the next session moves up,
and the timer resets for the new context.
The stage monitor isn't only useful when something is LIVE.
When a session is READY or
CALLING — meaning it's been flagged to start but
hasn't gone live yet — the monitor shows a different state.
The status line changes to 'STANDING BY —
STARTING SHORTLY' in amber.
The title and speaker are shown.
The timer shows the scheduled start time rather than a
countdown, and the colour is amber.
And if there's genuinely nothing active at all —
between events, or before the first session of the day
— the monitor shows 'STANDBY' with the event name,
and the next session details below it.
You still have context.
You're never looking at a blank screen.
To close the monitor, hit the small 'CLOSE' button in
the top right corner of the overlay.
That's it.
Your console comes back exactly as you left it —
nothing reloaded, no state lost.
You can also press Escape —
the keyboard handler recognises Escape as a dismiss for overlays,
so it works here too.
Stage Monitor isn't director-only.
The AV role and the signage role also have access
to the Stage Monitor button in their context panel.
The AV team can open it to keep track of
what's live while they're managing their equipment feeds.
The signage operator can use it to coordinate timing for manual override actions.
Stage and registration roles don't have the button,
because their views already surface what they need at a glance.
But any role that benefits from a dedicated confidence display
has access to it.
Simple feature, high value.
One button, full-screen context.
The monitor pulls from the same live data as everything
else in CueDeck — it's not a separate system or
a separate subscription, just a different view on the same state.
In the next episode we move from this director-facing display
to something the speaker themselves looks at: the Stage Timer.
That's a full-screen countdown designed to sit on a monitor
or tablet facing the stage —
so the presenter always knows exactly how much time they have.
See you there.