There's a problem that every conference speaker faces:
how do I know how much time I have left
without staring at the director?
The classic solution is a floor clock,
or a hand signal from the back of the room.
Both work — but neither is elegant,
and neither is visible if the speaker is moving around
or focused on a slide.
CueDeck's Stage Timer solves this cleanly.
It's a full-screen, colour-coded countdown that
you put on any screen facing the speaker —
a tablet on the lectern, a monitor at the back
of the stage, a TV at the side of the room.
The speaker glances at it and
instantly knows exactly where they stand.
No director intervention required.
Let's set one up and walk through every state it can be in.
The Stage Timer is a display mode in CueDeck's signage system.
That means you create it exactly like any other display:
open the Signage panel in the director console, click Add Display.
Give it a name — something like 'Stage Timer — Main Hall'.
Set the zone to 'stage'.
Set orientation to portrait if you're using a tablet or
a vertical monitor — the layout is designed to work
well in both orientations, but portrait is particularly good for
a tablet on a stand at the lectern.
For content mode, select 'stage-timer'.
Hit Save.
The display card appears.
Now click Open to get the URL.
There it is.
A large, full-screen timer.
Right now it's showing the standby state because we haven't
started a session yet.
Let's go through each state one by one.
When no session is currently LIVE or
on HOLD, the stage timer shows the standby state.
If there's a session coming up —
in READY, CALLING, or PLANNED state —
the display shows 'NEXT UP IN' at the top,
a large countdown to that session's scheduled start time in
the centre, and the session title and
speaker name at the bottom.
This is what the speaker sees as they're preparing backstage
or walking to the lectern.
They can see exactly how many minutes until their session
begins, and confirm they're looking at the right session title.
The moment a director clicks Go Live in the production
console, the stage timer updates automatically.
Supabase pushes the state change via its realtime channel and
the display re-renders within a second.
The green state: clean, calm, plenty of time.
The status badge at the top reads LIVE.
The timer in the centre is enormous —
we're talking the size that's readable from across a room.
Below it, a label reading 'REMAINING'.
Underneath the timer, the session title and speaker name.
And at the very bottom, a small 'NEXT:' line showing
the title of the next session in the programme —
so the speaker knows what's following them.
There's also a progress bar running across the width of
the screen, filling from left to right as the session time is consumed.
It's a visual secondary indicator —
useful for peripheral awareness even when
the number itself is hard to read at a distance.
At five minutes remaining, the timer colour shifts to amber.
No animation, no flash — a clean, smooth transition.
The label below the timer changes from 'REMAINING' to 'WRAPPING UP'.
The progress bar also turns amber to match.
This is the speaker's cue to start bringing their talk to a conclusion.
They don't need eye contact with the director,
they don't need a hand signal —
the screen is telling them.
At two minutes remaining, the timer turns red.
The label becomes 'ENDING NOW'.
This is the critical threshold —
the speaker has ninety seconds to wrap up and
hand back to the stage.
The red state is hard to ignore.
Even in a bright room, a red full-screen display gets attention.
The progress bar is now nearly full and also red.
When the session runs past its scheduled end time, the timer flips.
The status badge at the top now reads 'OVERTIME'.
The timer stops counting down and
starts counting up — showing a plus sign followed by
the number of minutes and seconds over time.
And the entire timer flashes.
Not subtle.
This is intentional — a speaker in OVERRUN needs an unmistakable signal.
The director in the production console sees the same OVERRUN
status on the session card, and
can choose to nudge the session —
extending its end time by one minute —
if they decide to give the speaker more room.
When a nudge is applied from the console,
the stage timer display picks it up immediately and
the countdown resumes from the extended time.
HOLD is the paused state —
used when AV needs to stop the session clock temporarily.
Maybe there's a technical problem, a fire alarm, an unexpected interruption.
When a session goes on HOLD in the production console,
the stage timer freezes.
The timer stops counting — it holds the exact remaining
time at the moment HOLD was triggered.
The colour shifts to orange.
The status badge changes to 'HOLD'.
The label below the timer reads 'PAUSED'.
This is important: the timer is frozen, not counting.
The speaker and the director both see the same frozen number.
When the session resumes — when
AV transitions it back to LIVE —
the countdown picks up from exactly where it stopped.
Time that was on hold doesn't count against the speaker's remaining time.
The Stage Timer is designed to work in portrait orientation
as well as landscape.
Portrait is ideal for a tablet on a lectern stand
— the long axis of the screen means the timer
can be even larger, and the session title and
next session footer have more vertical space.
To use portrait, just set orientation to portrait when
you create or edit the display in the signage panel.
The display page adapts its layout automatically.
In practice: buy a cheap tablet mount,
prop it on the lectern, open the display URL in
full screen, lock the screen orientation.
That's your speaker timer.
No hardware, no timecode, no dedicated timer device.
One quick note on access: directors and
stage managers can open the Stage Timer display directly from
the context panel in the production console —
there's a 'STAGE TIMER' button in the Monitor section,
right next to the Stage Monitor button.
Clicking it opens the configured Stage Timer display URL in a new tab.
If no Stage Timer display has been set up yet,
CueDeck will show a toast notification and
scroll the signage panel into view so you can create
one on the spot.
The Stage Timer is a simple concept executed well.
One URL, open on any screen facing the stage,
and your speakers are self-managing their own time with zero director overhead.
Set it up once, and it runs for the entire event.
Every session transition, every delay, every HOLD —
it all reflects automatically.
That wraps up this episode.
In the next one we're going into the AI agent
modules — the Incident Advisor, the Cue Engine,
and the Post-Event Report Generator.
See you there.