Most production problems don't happen in the first minute of a session.
They happen in the seven minutes before it,
when someone forgot to check the microphone battery,
or the slides are still on the wrong laptop,
or nobody confirmed the interpreter booth is on channel two.
The Cue Engine is CueDeck's answer to that.
It watches your session schedule, and
eight minutes before every session's planned start time,
it fires a modal with a tailored pre-cue checklist —
generated by AI, specific to that session.
Let me show you exactly what happens.
A pre-cue is a standard stage management concept.
It's the window of time —
typically between five and ten minutes before a session —
where you run your final checks.
Speaker arrived and miked up?
Slides confirmed and on the opening frame?
AV routing confirmed?
Streaming encoder hot and stable?
Interpretation channels live?
Traditionally this lives on a paper checklist or
in your stage manager's head.
The Cue Engine puts it in CueDeck,
makes it specific to each session,
and makes sure it actually fires at the right moment — automatically.
The engine fires eight minutes before the session's scheduled start.
That gives you time to catch a problem and actually fix it.
Here's what you see when the Cue Engine fires.
The modal slides in with an orange accent —
distinct from the red of the Incident Advisor —
because this is a warning, not a crisis.
At the top: the session title, start time, and room.
Below that, the countdown timer.
Right now it shows seven minutes and
fifty-eight seconds, ticking down in real time.
When you get under two minutes the timer turns red
and starts blinking — a final visual prompt that
you're about to miss your window.
Below the timer is a progress bar.
It depletes as time runs out.
You can see at a glance how much of your
pre-cue window you've used.
And here is the part that
makes the Cue Engine more than just a timer.
While the modal is opening, Claude is generating a checklist
specific to this session.
It knows the session title, the room,
the start time, and any notes you've attached to the session.
From that, it builds a prioritised list of pre-cue tasks
— not generic ones, but ones appropriate to what this session actually involves.
For a panel discussion with four wireless microphones,
you'll see items about confirming all four mic packs are charged and live.
For a session with Polish and
German interpretation, there'll be a booth check item for both channels.
For a keynote with a streaming feed,
the encoder status check will be there.
Each item has a coloured tag on the right:
CREW items are blue, SYSTEM items are orange,
INTERP items are purple.
At a glance you can see what category each task
falls into and who owns it.
As you confirm each item with your team, click it.
It turns green, strikes through, and
the completion counter at the bottom updates.
If your stage manager is calling in confirmations over comms,
you're clicking them off in real time.
When everything is checked, hit CUE READY at the bottom right.
The modal closes, CueDeck logs the confirmation,
and you're cleared to go live when
the session hits its start time.
If you need a moment —
you're in the middle of another conversation —
hit SNOOZE 2 MIN.
The modal dismisses and re-fires two minutes later so nothing gets missed.
Here's the real value of the Cue Engine:
it removes the need to remember to do your pre-cue checks.
On a long conference day —
ten sessions across three rooms, back-to-back panels,
speaker changes every forty-five minutes —
it is very easy to miss the eight-minute window for
a session because you're handling something else.
The engine watches every session's start time simultaneously and
fires the modal when each one is due.
You don't have to set alarms,
you don't have to watch the clock,
you don't have to maintain a separate checklist document.
And because the checklist is AI-generated and
session-specific, it adapts to each cue.
A registration desk walkthrough gets different items than a technical
keynote with a livestream.
That's the Cue Engine.
Eight minutes before every session, a tailored readiness checklist fires
automatically — no setup required, no alarms to set,
no paper lists to maintain.
In the next episode we're covering the third and
final AI agent: the Post-Event Report Generator.
After your event wraps, one click generates a full written
debrief — summary stats, variance table,
incident log, and a narrative written by Claude that
you can send directly to your client.
I'll see you there.