The last session has ended.
The speakers are packing up.
The room is clearing out.
And somewhere in the next 48 hours,
you need to send your client a debrief —
how the day ran, how close you were to schedule,
what incidents happened and how they were handled.
Normally that document takes two hours.
You're pulling times from your notes,
cross-referencing with the programme, trying to remember which
AV issue happened in which room and
what the fix was.
The CueDeck Report Generator does all of that in one click.
Let me show you.
The Report Generator is the third AI agent module,
in the AI Agents panel.
It's director-only — same as the other two agents —
because this is a document that
will go to your client or your internal team.
Click Generate Report and the process starts immediately.
CueDeck pulls all the data it needs from the current
event — session records, scheduled versus actual times,
the incident log, everything that happened during the day —
and passes it to Claude to generate the report.
While the report generates you'll see this thinking animation —
five steps cycling through, each one lighting up as the
AI works through that phase of the report.
Session analysis, incident processing, metric calculation, summary drafting, recommendations.
This typically takes fifteen to twenty seconds.
When it finishes, the tabs appear and
the content is ready.
The first tab is Summary —
and this is what I'd open if I were sending
something to a client.
At the top, four stat cards:
total sessions run today, the on-time rate as a percentage,
the average overrun across all sessions,
and the total number of incidents logged.
These are pulled from your actual session data — not estimates.
Below that, two written sections generated by Claude:
an Executive Summary — three to four sentences,
professional tone, suitable for a client email —
and a Technical Performance paragraph covering AV system reliability,
streaming stability, and crew execution.
This is the kind of language that
normally takes thirty minutes to write.
It's already there, it's accurate, and
it's based on what actually happened today.
The Sessions tab is your variance table.
Every session, side by side: planned start time versus actual
start time, and the delta in minutes.
Green deltas mean on time or early.
Orange means a minor overrun — within a few minutes.
Red means it ran significantly late.
You can see at a glance where
the day was tight and where it slipped.
This table is what you'd use for your internal debrief
— understanding which rooms ran well,
which sessions need buffer time added next year,
whether the lunch break was long enough.
It's also useful for invoice justification if you're billing for
overtime on a specific room.
The Incidents tab is the log of everything that
was flagged through the Incident Advisor during the day.
Each entry shows the time it was triggered,
the system affected, the location, the description you typed when
you raised it, and the final status — resolved or escalated.
If you had two incidents during the day and
both were resolved on-site, this tab tells that story clearly.
If one was escalated to a senior technician,
that's logged here too.
For a client-facing debrief, this is the section you use
to explain what went wrong and
what was done about it.
Transparent, timestamped, factual.
The fourth tab is where the report really earns its place.
This is the AI Narrative —
a full written debrief generated by Claude,
covering how the day ran in plain professional English.
It synthesises everything: the session count,
the schedule adherence, the incidents, the technical environment,
and the crew's execution.
The result reads like something written by a senior production
manager reflecting on the event —
because in a sense, that's exactly what it is.
Below the narrative, a numbered recommendations list.
Four to five items, specific and
actionable: add buffer time before the closing keynote,
assign a dedicated stream monitor for events above five hundred
online attendees, confirm EDID compatibility for the main stage switcher before doors open.
Real recommendations based on what actually happened today.
Once you're happy with the report,
two export options are in the footer.
Copy Text puts the full report onto your clipboard as
plain text — ready to paste into an email,
a Google Doc, or a Notion page.
Print / PDF opens the browser print dialog, formatted for print.
From there you can save as a PDF and
attach it to your client debrief,
or print it for your own records.
The report includes the event name,
date, and a generated timestamp —
so it's clearly identified and ready to send.
Three main use cases for this.
Client debrief: copy the Executive Summary and
the Incidents log and send it within the hour.
Clients appreciate fast, professional follow-through.
Internal review: use the Sessions variance table in your next production planning meeting.
The overruns tell you where to add buffer in the schedule next time.
Invoice justification: if you're billing for additional crew time or
technical callouts, the incident log and
timestamps give you the documentation to back it up.
One click.
Full report.
Ready to send.
That's the Report Generator — the third and
final AI agent in CueDeck.
Combined with the Incident Advisor and
the Cue Engine, you have an AI co-pilot that
runs with you through the entire event:
prevention before it starts, response when
something breaks, and documentation when it's done.
In the next episode we're getting into signage —
specifically the Timeline and Programme display modes.
If you've ever wanted an attendee-facing screen that
shows the day's schedule in real time and
updates automatically as sessions go live, that's the episode.
I'll see you there.