Attendees at a conference shouldn't need to check their phones
to know what's on next.
They should be able to look up at a screen
and see exactly what's happening now,
what's coming up, and where it is.
CueDeck has two signage modes built specifically for this: Timeline and Programme.
Timeline is a vertical chronological list —
great for lobby screens and corridor monitors.
Programme is a time-by-room grid —
the kind of grid you'd see on a large conference board.
Both update in realtime as your sessions go live, overrun, or end.
Let me walk you through setting them both up.
Signage is managed from the Signage panel in CueDeck —
accessible from the left sidebar.
Each display you've configured shows here as a card:
its name, zone type, orientation, and
the current content mode.
If you haven't set up any displays yet,
there's an Add Display button at the top.
Each display corresponds to a physical screen somewhere in your
venue — a lobby monitor, a stage confidence screen, a hallway TV.
For today's episode, I already have a few displays configured.
We'll edit two of them —
one for Timeline and one for Programme.
To set a display to Timeline mode,
open it in the Signage panel and
set the Content Mode to Timeline.
That's it — one dropdown.
But there are two options worth understanding:
scroll style and paginate.
Scroll means the list animates continuously from bottom to top
— like a news ticker, but
for your conference schedule.
This is ideal for a screen that's visible from a
distance and people are glancing at while walking past.
It's always moving, always showing new content.
Paginate means the list shows a full page of sessions,
holds for a set number of seconds —
you configure this, typically between eight and
fifteen seconds — and then advances to the next page.
This is better for a screen where
people are standing and reading, because the content stays still
long enough to be read properly.
I'll set this one to Paginate,
ten seconds per page, and save it.
Here's what the display looks like.
Timeline mode renders a vertical chronological list of all sessions
for the day — time on the left,
session title and room on the right.
The LIVE session has a green indicator —
it stands out immediately on a dark screen from across a lobby.
Sessions that have already ended are visually dimmed,
so the focus naturally falls on what's current and upcoming.
Future sessions are at full brightness.
This updates in realtime.
When a director hits Go Live in the console,
that session's status on this screen changes within a second
— no refresh, no delay.
A lobby screen running Timeline is always accurate.
Now let's set up Programme mode.
Same process — open the display,
set the Content Mode dropdown to Programme.
Where Timeline is a vertical list,
Programme renders as a grid: time slots run down the
left side, rooms run across the top.
Each cell in the grid shows the session in that
room at that time.
It reads exactly like the printed conference programme that
delegates pick up at registration.
This is the mode you want on a large-format screen
— a wide television in the main lobby,
a display at the registration desk,
or a screen at the entrance to the session floor
where people are choosing which room to go to.
Here's the Programme grid.
Rooms across the top — Hall A,
Hall B, Workshop Room, Breakout —
and time slots down the left.
Each session sits in the correct cell.
The currently LIVE session has a green highlight in its cell.
As sessions end and new ones go live,
the grid updates automatically.
You can also configure the paginate setting for Programme mode,
exactly the same as Timeline.
If you have a very large conference —
a lot of rooms, a lot of time slots —
the grid might not fit on one screen,
so you configure pages with an automatic advance interval.
For most single-day conferences with three to five rooms,
the Programme grid fits comfortably on a 55-inch screen in landscape orientation.
Quick comparison so the difference is clear.
Scroll is best for: lobby corridors,
anywhere screens are glanced at while moving,
long session lists that would take multiple pages.
Paginate is best for: screens where
people stop to read, registration desk displays,
anywhere the audience is stationary.
The paginate interval — how many seconds per page —
is set per display.
You can tune it independently for each screen.
A large lobby screen might flip every twelve seconds.
A registration desk screen might sit for twenty seconds because
delegates are standing there reading every line.
Both settings are saved per display and
persist across sessions and page refreshes.
This is worth seeing live.
On the left, the director console.
On the right, the Timeline display.
I'll click Go Live on the next session —
and watch what happens on the display.
The session immediately gets a green LIVE badge.
The previous session dims to ENDED.
The whole list reflows.
All of this happens via a Supabase realtime subscription —
the display page is listening for postgres changes on the
session table and re-renders as soon as any status changes.
Your venue's displays are always showing the current state of the event.
Timeline for corridors and lobbies.
Programme for overview screens and registration areas.
Both update live, both support scroll and
paginate, both are configured from the Signage panel in under a minute.
In the next episode, the final piece of the signage system: sponsor logos.
How to upload your sponsor branding,
configure rotation timing, and build a display sequence that
rotates between the sponsor mode and
the session modes automatically.
That one is short and practical —
I'll see you there.