Every conference has sponsors.
And every sponsor expects to see their logo on the screens.
In CueDeck, the Sponsor signage mode handles this automatically —
you upload the logos, set how long each one displays,
and they rotate in a clean fade loop on any
display you assign them to.
In this episode I'll show you how to upload sponsors,
configure timing, and build a display sequence that
rotates between sponsor branding and your session content automatically.
Sponsor logos are managed from the Signage panel.
There's a dedicated Sponsors section here —
separate from your display configuration —
where you manage the sponsor list that
feeds the Sponsor mode.
Each sponsor has a name, a logo file,
and a display duration in seconds.
The list feeds every display that
is set to Sponsor mode —
so you manage the logos once,
and they appear on all the relevant screens.
You can also set a sort order,
which controls the rotation sequence.
Let's add a sponsor.
Click Add Sponsor.
You'll get a small form: the sponsor's name,
a logo upload, and display duration in seconds.
For the logo file: the recommended format is PNG with a transparent background.
This is important — the Sponsor mode renders on a
dark background, so a PNG with transparency will look clean and professional.
A white-background JPEG will look like a white rectangle in
the middle of a dark screen.
Recommended size is 800 by 600 pixels or larger.
CueDeck scales the image to fit the display,
so going bigger is fine — it won't pixelate.
Going smaller may look soft on a large TV.
I'll upload this sponsor logo, set the name to Platinum
Partner, and set the display duration to eight seconds.
Hit Save — the logo uploads to the leod-assets storage
bucket and the sponsor is added to the rotation immediately.
Add as many sponsors as you need.
Each one gets its own duration setting —
so if your title sponsor paid more,
you can give them twelve seconds while other sponsors get six.
The rotation respects the individual durations per sponsor,
not a global setting.
The sort order determines the rotation sequence.
Drag to reorder, or manually set the order number —
your title sponsor can always appear first.
Once the logos are uploaded, they're live immediately on any
display running Sponsor mode.
No page refresh, no redeploy —
the display picks up the new sponsor via the realtime subscription.
To show sponsors on a specific screen,
open the display in the Signage panel and
set the Content Mode to Sponsors.
That display will now rotate through your sponsor list,
each logo displayed for its configured duration.
Here's what it looks like.
Clean, centred, full-screen logo on a dark background.
After the configured duration, it fades out and
the next sponsor fades in.
The transitions are smooth — no flash, no hard cut.
If a sponsor has no logo uploaded —
just a name — the mode renders the name in large text instead.
So you're never showing a broken image placeholder.
The most practical setup for venue displays isn't a screen
that shows sponsors full-time.
It's a screen that cycles between useful session content and sponsor branding automatically.
CueDeck has a sequence builder for exactly this.
In the display edit modal, scroll down to the Sequence
section and enable it.
Then build your rotation: add a slide for the NextUp
mode — the card showing what's on stage now and
what's coming next — and set it to run for thirty seconds.
Add a second slide for Sponsors mode and
set it to ten seconds.
Save the display.
Now it runs: thirty seconds of NextUp,
ten seconds of sponsors, back to NextUp,
back to sponsors — automatically, indefinitely.
You can build sequences with as many slides as you
need, combining any of CueDeck's ten display modes:
NextUp, Timeline, Programme, Sponsors, Clock, Countdown, and more.
Each slide has its own duration.
A few practical tips for sponsor logos that
look professional on venue screens.
Always use PNG with transparency.
Never JPEG.
Minimum 800 by 600 pixels.
For a 4K screen, go 1600 by 900.
If a sponsor only gives you a JPEG,
open it in any image editor,
remove the white background, and export as PNG.
Ten minutes of prep prevents an embarrassing white box on
a display during the coffee break.
Duration: eight to ten seconds is the sweet spot.
Long enough to read, short enough to keep rotating.
Avoid anything shorter than five seconds —
logos need a moment to register.
And if you're running the Sequence mode —
mixing sponsors with session content —
the sponsor duration within the sequence is separate from the per-logo rotation duration.
The sequence controls how long the display spends in Sponsor mode total.
The per-logo duration controls how quickly it cycles through individual
sponsors within that window.
Upload your logos, set durations, build a sequence that
mixes sponsor time with session content,
and every screen in the venue is handling your sponsor commitments automatically.
That wraps up the signage series —
Timeline, Programme, and Sponsors.
In the next episode we're going deeper into the display
system: the full sequence builder, all ten display modes,
and how to configure a multi-zone venue where
different screens show different content for different audiences.
Subscribe so you don't miss it.