Here's a scenario.
You're running a live keynote.
The speaker is thirty seconds from wrapping.
You need to end this session,
set the next one to ready,
and trigger a broadcast — all in the next ninety seconds.
The stage manager is on comms asking for a cue.
The client is standing next to you asking how the schedule looks.
You don't have time to move a mouse to the
right place and click three different buttons.
You need to work fast, with your eyes on the room.
CueDeck has a full keyboard shortcut system built for exactly this.
Let me show you everything.
The `?` key opens the shortcut reference.
You don't have to memorise anything —
this panel is always one keypress away.
On the left, the navigation shortcuts.
On the right, help and general commands.
Every shortcut in the app is listed here.
Let me walk through the ones you'll actually use every day.
The `/` key focuses the search bar instantly.
Start typing a session name and
the list filters in real time — no mouse required.
`B` opens the broadcast bar.
You can type a message and
hit Enter without ever leaving the keyboard.
`R` sets the selected session to READY.
One key, one action — as long as the session
is in a state that allows it.
`Escape` closes any open modal, dismisses the broadcast bar,
clears the search — your universal exit key.
And `Cmd+K` — or `Ctrl+K` on Windows —
opens the command palette.
That one gets its own section.
Press `/` and the cursor jumps straight into the search field.
I start typing 'workshop' and the session list filters immediately.
Everything else disappears.
I can see exactly what I need.
Arrow key down to navigate, Escape to clear and get everything back.
For a 30-session event with three rooms,
this is how you find anything in under two seconds.
Press `B` and the broadcast bar opens at the top
of the screen — ready to type.
I type my message — 'Sarah Chen please make your
way to the Main Stage' — and hit Enter.
That message goes to every connected device in under a second.
No menu.
No clicking.
Just `B`, type, Enter.
The character counter updates as I type so I know
I'm within the display limit for signage screens.
And if I change my mind,
`Escape` closes the bar without sending anything.
This is the command palette, and
it's the fastest way to do anything in CueDeck —
especially if you already know what you want.
It searches across two things simultaneously:
your live sessions, and a set of static commands.
Start typing and it fuzzy-matches against both.
Type 'keyn' and I get the two keynote sessions.
I can navigate the list with the up and
down arrows — watch the highlight move.
Press Enter and I jump straight to that
session in the list.
The context panel opens on the right,
ready for me to take action.
Type 'go live' and the static 'Go Live' command appears
— pressing Enter on that triggers the Go Live action
on the currently selected session.
No clicking required.
The palette closes the moment I confirm an action.
`Escape` at any point closes it without doing anything.
The keyboard navigation is fully consistent:
up and down arrows to move through results,
Enter to confirm, Escape to exit.
Once you know those three keys you can use the
palette entirely without touching the mouse.
The `R` shortcut is a single-key action —
it sets the selected session to READY immediately,
without opening any modal.
This is the shortcut that gets used more than any
other in a live run.
You've just ended a session, you select the next one
in the list, you hit `R`.
The stage manager gets the READY signal instantly.
Then you pick up your radio.
Three keypresses to advance the programme:
click the next session, `R`, done.
Or if you're on the command palette,
you don't even need the click.
Let me run through a realistic sequence using nothing but the keyboard.
Watch.
End the current session — I'll use the command palette.
`Cmd+K`, type 'end', select End Session, Enter.
Session 1 is now ENDED.
Select session 2 — arrow key down in the session
list, Enter to open it.
Hit `R` — session 2 is now READY.
Broadcast the speaker call — `B`,
type 'Marco Rossi to the stage please', Enter.
Done.
Check the schedule — `/`, type the next session name, Escape to return.
Entire sequence.
No mouse.
Twelve keypresses.
In a high-pressure moment on a live stage,
that speed is real.
It's the difference between keeping up with the show and falling behind it.
Keyboard shortcuts and the command palette are the production professional's interface.
They reward the operators who invest ten minutes learning them
with a measurably faster, smoother, less error-prone show day.
The full reference is always one `?` away.
Start with the four essentials: `?` for help,
`B` for broadcast, `/` for search,
`Cmd+K` for everything else.
The rest will come naturally.
Next episode: CueDeck on mobile and tablet.
How the layout adapts, practical setups for stage managers on
an iPad and registration on a phone,
and what you need to know about running realtime production
on a handheld device.
I'll see you there.