One of the questions I get asked most often about
CueDeck is: does it work on a tablet?
What about a phone?
Can my stage manager use it on an iPad?
The answer is yes — and
in this episode I'll show you exactly what that looks like.
CueDeck is a browser app, which
means it runs on any device with a modern browser
and an internet connection.
The layout adapts to the screen it's on.
Let me show you how.
I'll use the browser's device emulation tools so you can
see the responsive layout clearly.
This is what CueDeck looks like on an iPad in portrait orientation.
Notice what's changed.
The role bar — the strip of role buttons at
the top — has wrapped onto two lines instead of
trying to squeeze into one.
The session list takes up the full width of the screen.
The context panel, which on desktop sits to the right
of the session list, moves to a sheet that
slides up from the bottom when
you tap a session.
On a tablet the interaction model is tap-first.
Tap a session to select it.
The action sheet comes up.
Tap the action button to trigger the transition.
It works exactly the same as the desktop version —
just with your thumb instead of a mouse.
The context panel sheet uses the same data,
the same real-time sync, and the same state machine.
Nothing is simplified or removed —
it's the same production tool.
Here's the setup I'd recommend for a stage manager running a single room.
They're in Stage role.
They have an iPad on a stand or
a table just offstage — portrait orientation,
tablet stand, screen always on.
They can see the entire session list for their room
— filter by room, and only their sessions are showing.
When a speaker arrives they tap the session,
tap Speaker Arrived, the director sees it immediately.
When it's time to go live —
if the stage manager has that
permission — one tap, one confirmation,
the session is live.
No radio call needed.
The director sees it on their screen the same moment
the stage manager taps the button.
The buttons are large enough for reliable touch input.
There's no tiny click target that's easy to misfire when you're under pressure.
The state machine still enforces all the same rules —
you can't accidentally put something LIVE that isn't READY first.
Now let's look at a phone —
this is the registration desk use case.
The Registration role has the simplest view in CueDeck:
the upcoming session queue, who's on next,
and a read-only status of what's live right now.
That's all the information a registration team needs —
they're not running transitions, they're answering attendee questions.
On a phone that view stacks cleanly.
Session cards fill the full width,
the current status badge is large enough to read at
a glance, and the next session's speaker name and title are prominent.
A registration team member can keep this open on their
personal phone or a shared device at the desk,
and the screen updates automatically without a refresh.
The moment the director takes a session LIVE, it appears here.
No app to install.
They sign in, pick their role,
and the screen stays live all day.
For directors who run on a laptop with a tablet
beside them — this is a useful configuration.
The tablet is your second monitor.
Open CueDeck in Safari on the iPad,
keep it in landscape orientation, and
you have the full director view with all controls available.
Some directors I've spoken to use the tablet specifically for
the signage panel — they keep their signage displays open
on the iPad so they can monitor what's showing on
the venue screens without switching windows on their laptop.
Two views, one account, fully synced.
A few practical tips for mobile and tablet setups.
First: use a dedicated browser tab,
not a general browsing session.
Keep CueDeck as its own pinned tab on the device.
It's easier to find under pressure.
Second: on iOS, you can add CueDeck to your Home
Screen from Safari — tap the share button and
choose 'Add to Home Screen'.
It opens full-screen like a native app, no browser chrome.
That's a cleaner experience on an iPad in portrait on a stand.
Third: keep the screen on.
Most tablets dim the display after a minute of no interaction.
Go into your device settings and
set the screen timeout to 'Never' or
the longest available option for show day.
You don't want the screen going dark while you're watching a speaker.
Fourth: about internet connectivity.
CueDeck requires an active internet connection for realtime sync —
it's communicating with Supabase for every state change and every broadcast.
If you're backstage at a venue with unreliable WiFi,
test your connection before the event starts.
A strong 4G signal on a mobile data connection is a reliable fallback.
CueDeck works on any modern browser, on any device.
The layout adapts, the touch targets are the right size,
and every role is usable on a phone or
tablet without any feature degradation.
For most production teams the sweet spot is:
director on a laptop, stage managers on tablets, registration on phones.
Everyone connected, everyone synced, no one staring at a laptop
screen when they should be watching the stage.
Next episode is about billing —
the plans, the pricing, how the per-event credit option works,
and how to upgrade when your team is ready.
I'll see you there.