CueDeck has a free plan, a Pro plan,
and an Enterprise option.
It also has something a bit unusual:
a per-event credit system for production teams who run events
occasionally rather than continuously.
In this episode I'll walk through all four options —
what you get, what the limits are,
when each one makes sense —
and I'll show you where to find your current usage
and how to upgrade directly from the console.
There are three subscription plans and one credit option.
Free gives you one active event at a time,
up to five operators, two signage displays.
No AI features, no post-event reports.
It's enough to run your first event and
evaluate whether CueDeck fits your workflow.
No credit card required to sign up.
Pro is €79 per month.
Unlimited events, up to twenty operators,
unlimited signage displays, full AI agent access —
Incident Advisor, Cue Engine, Report Generator —
and post-event report exports.
This is the plan for teams running regular events:
conferences, summits, roadshows, anything recurring.
Enterprise is custom pricing.
Unlimited operators, dedicated support, custom onboarding,
SLA agreements, and volume invoicing.
If you're running large-scale events with 50-person production crews or
you need a contract and procurement process,
Enterprise is the path.
And then there's Per-Event credit.
This is for the production professional who runs two or
three events a year — maybe a freelancer,
maybe a team that handles occasional corporate events.
You buy a single event credit,
it unlocks Pro features for one event,
and when that event ends the credit is consumed.
No monthly commitment.
Your current plan status is always one click away —
in the user profile panel.
Click your name chip in the header.
At the top of the panel:
your name, your role, and a plan badge.
If you're on Free it shows FREE in grey.
Pro shows PRO in blue.
Enterprise shows ENTERPRISE in purple.
Below that, usage bars.
If you're on the Free plan you can see exactly
how many events you're using out of your one allowed.
If you're on Pro the bars show operator count and
display count versus your limits.
These update in real time —
as soon as you create an event or
invite an operator, the bar adjusts.
This is useful not just for tracking your own usage
but for explaining your limits to a client or
a team member: 'we're on Free,
we have one event — to run the second event
we need to upgrade.'
The Billing button inside the profile panel launches the Stripe checkout directly.
CueDeck uses Stripe for all payment processing —
it's the same payment infrastructure used by most major SaaS
products, so your card details are handled by Stripe,
not stored by CueDeck.
On the checkout screen you'll see the plan options:
Pro at €79 per month billed monthly,
and Per-Event credit at the current per-event rate for a single-use unlock.
Select your plan, enter your card details, and confirm.
The upgrade is applied immediately —
your plan badge in the profile panel updates,
the usage limits change, and AI features unlock without a page refresh.
CueDeck also supports VAT invoicing for European businesses.
The checkout asks for your billing address and
VAT number if applicable — invoices with proper VAT line
items are generated automatically by Stripe.
Once you're on a paid plan,
the Manage Subscription link in the profile panel takes you
to the Stripe customer portal.
From there you can change your payment method,
update your billing address, download past invoices as PDFs,
or cancel your subscription.
Invoice history is important for production companies billing clients —
every monthly charge generates a proper Stripe invoice with a
unique number, your billing address, and the line item.
Download it, forward it to your accounts department, done.
The practical decision tree: If you're just evaluating CueDeck — start Free.
Sign up, create your event, run it,
see if the workflow fits.
No cost, no commitment.
If you run events regularly —
monthly or more often, or multiple events per year with
large crews — Pro at €79 a month is straightforward value.
The AI agents alone justify it on any professional production.
If you run one or two events a year and
don't want a monthly subscription —
Per-Event credit is built for you.
Buy it when you need it,
it unlocks for that event, and
you're not paying €79 in the months you're not working.
If you're an event management company,
a large AV house, or you need procurement process,
SLA, or volume pricing — talk to the Enterprise team.
There's a contact link on the pricing page.
The pricing is designed so that
the tool pays for itself.
One session overrun caught early by the Cue Engine can
save thirty minutes of programme time.
One well-written client debrief from the Report Generator can win the next contract.
The numbers work.
That's the full billing picture —
Free for evaluation, Per-Event for occasional users,
Pro for regular production teams, and
Enterprise for large organisations.
Your usage is always visible in the profile panel,
upgrading takes two minutes through Stripe,
and you can download invoices any time.
In the next episode we're going deep on multi-room and
multi-track events — how to use room filters,
the Programme signage view, anchor sessions,
and how to run a three-track conference without losing your mind.
I'll see you there.