If you've been following this series,
you've seen CueDeck running a single room.
One stage, one session list, one set of transitions.
Now let's scale it up.
In this episode we're running a three-track conference —
a main plenary stage and two parallel workshop rooms running simultaneously.
This is where CueDeck's multi-room features come in.
I'll show you how to set up rooms,
how to filter the view per room,
how to use the Programme signage display to show the
full grid to attendees, and how anchor sessions keep your
programme together when one track falls behind.
Every session in CueDeck has a Room field.
It's a free-text input — you type the room name and save it.
There's no separate room setup required;
the room names are generated by whatever you type.
For a three-track event, I'd use consistent names across all
sessions: 'Main Stage', 'Workshop A', 'Workshop B'.
Capitalisation and spacing matter here —
'Workshop A' and 'workshop a' would show as two separate
rooms in the filter bar, so pick a format and
stick with it across your whole programme.
Once you've set rooms on your sessions,
the filter bar at the top of the session list
automatically generates a chip for each unique room name.
You don't configure this anywhere —
it builds itself from the data.
With three rooms, you'll see three room chips in the filter bar.
Click one to isolate that room.
Click it again to clear the filter and see everything.
Click Workshop A — the session list immediately shows only Workshop A sessions.
Everything else is hidden.
This is the primary tool for a multi-room event.
Each stage manager running their own room filters to their
room and ignores the rest.
The director can see everything or filter as needed.
The filter works alongside the status filter and the search bar.
So you can filter to Workshop A AND
only READY or LIVE sessions at the same time.
In a large event with thirty or
forty sessions across five rooms, that combination is essential.
Click another room chip to switch to that room.
Click the active chip to deselect it.
The filter state is persisted through the current session —
close and reopen the context panel and
your filter stays active.
For a multi-room event, I typically structure the team by room.
The director has the full view —
all three rooms, all sessions.
Each stage manager is assigned to one room and
filters their view to that room from the start of the day.
They see only what they need to see and
act only on their sessions.
The director broadcasts messages to everyone,
monitors the full programme from above,
and handles cross-room decisions like delay cascades.
The stage managers handle the ground-level transitions for their room.
This structure scales cleanly.
Adding a fourth room means inviting one more stage manager
and telling them their room name —
no additional setup required.
Now for one of the most important concepts in multi-room
delay management: anchor sessions.
An anchor session is a plenary moment —
lunch break, networking session, closing keynote,
registration — that affects every room.
When the main stage runs long and
you apply a delay to Workshop A,
the delay cascade rolls forward through that room's subsequent sessions.
But it stops at the next anchor session.
The anchor holds its position.
It doesn't shift.
Because lunch starts at thirteen hundred whether Workshop A's morning
panel ran six minutes over or not.
The catering team, the hotel, the signage in the lobby
— all of that is fixed to the anchor time.
Look at what happens when I apply a five-minute delay
to this Workshop B session.
The sessions below it in Workshop B shift forward by
five minutes — that's the cascade doing its job.
But the Networking Lunch session, which
is marked as an anchor, stays exactly where it is.
It does not absorb the delay.
The practical implication: your workshop sessions will need to compress
slightly before the anchor, or you accept that
the final pre-lunch session ends a bit late.
That's a call for the director,
and CueDeck gives you the information to make it in real time.
Anchor sessions have a visual marker on their card —
a small indicator that tells you at a glance 'this one doesn't move'.
Scan the session list and you can immediately see which
sessions are the fixed points of your programme.
The Programme display mode is the master view for a multi-track event.
It renders a time-by-room grid —
rows running down the left are time slots,
columns across the top are your room names.
Every session appears in the correct cell at the correct time.
Put this on a large screen in the main lobby
or the registration area and attendees can see the entire
day's programme at a glance —
every track, every room, every time slot,
all in one view.
As sessions go live they update in real time.
A session that's running five minutes late will show its
updated time if you've applied a delay cascade.
The Programme mode reads from the same session data as the console.
There's no separate configuration for the grid —
it builds from your session room names and scheduled times automatically.
Add a room by assigning sessions to a new room
name, and the column appears in the Programme display.
Three practical things I've learned from running multi-room events on CueDeck.
First: set your anchor sessions before the event starts.
Identify all the plenary moments —
lunch, networking breaks, the closing keynote —
and mark them as anchors in the session edit modal.
This takes five minutes and saves you from accidentally cascading
a delay into a fixed point.
Second: use room naming conventions your whole team knows before show day.
Brief everyone: 'our rooms are Main Stage,
Workshop A, Workshop B.' One naming convention, communicated in advance.
Third: for delay decisions, the director filters to the affected
room, sees the cascade, decides if it's acceptable or
needs a broadcast to attendees.
That decision should happen within sixty seconds of the overrun
starting — the delay cascade makes the impact visible immediately.
Multi-room events are where CueDeck earns its place in a professional production toolkit.
Room filters, per-room delay cascades, anchor sessions,
and the Programme signage grid all work together to give
you control over a complex programme without losing the overview.
The next episode — Episode 21 —
is the capstone of this series.
We're running a full event, uncut,
from blank console to post-event report.
Tech Summit 2026, ten sessions, three rooms, one live run-through.
Everything we've covered in this series in one complete demo.
I'll see you there.