It's eight forty-five on the morning of Tech Summit 2026.
Doors open in fifteen minutes, the first session starts in seventy-five.
I've got ten sessions loaded across two rooms,
three signage displays running, and a stage manager connecting from
the Main Stage right now.
This is a full event run on CueDeck —
no cuts, no feature callouts, just a complete show day
from first check to last session.
Let's go.
First thing every morning: programme check.
I need to confirm every session is in place before
anyone steps on stage.
Ten sessions.
Seven on Main Stage, three on Workshop B.
Let me run through them.
Session 1: Registration & Welcome Break —
Main Stage — 09:00 to 09:30.
PLANNED.
Session 2: Opening Keynote — Sarah Chen —
Main Stage — 09:30 to 10:15.
PLANNED.
Session 3: Product Deep Dive —
Alex Morgan — Main Stage — 10:15 to 11:00.
PLANNED.
Workshop B Panel — 10:15 parallel —
three sessions, all PLANNED.
The anchor sessions are in place:
Coffee Break at 11:00 and Networking Lunch at 13:00.
Closing Keynote — 16:00 — anchor.
All confirmed.
Programme is clean.
No orphaned sessions, no missing speakers.
The clock sync indicator in the header is green —
we're live with the database.
Three displays up this morning.
The Lobby Board is in Timeline mode —
attendees can see the full day schedule as they come in.
It's on the screen in the registration area.
Main Stage Timer is in Stage Timer mode —
this is the countdown clock on the confidence monitor facing the speakers.
It'll start running the moment the session goes LIVE.
Main Stage Confidence is the full confidence monitor —
speaker name, session title, time remaining, current status.
On a screen facing the stage, visible to the presenter.
Displays are running.
Lobby board is showing the full programme.
We're ready to receive the first attendees.
Emma is online.
Stage manager for Main Stage —
she signed in from the iPad on the stage wing
about two minutes ago.
I can see her connection status in the header.
Emma, we're good.
Programme is confirmed.
Your first cue is Registration at nine hundred — stand by.
Eight fifty-eight.
Two minutes before the published start.
Registration goes READY.
Emma sees that on her iPad.
Attendees are at the doors.
Nine oh-one.
Doors are open, welcome music is on.
Session 1 is LIVE.
The stage timer is running.
The lobby board has flipped the Registration session to active.
Nine twenty-eight — registration wraps two minutes early.
Session 1 ENDED.
Good start.
Session 2 goes READY at nine twenty-eight.
Sarah should be in the wings.
I'll call her to stage.
CALLING state.
Emma sees this on her iPad —
that's her cue to walk Sarah to the stage entrance.
Broadcast sent.
Every operator in the room knows where
Sarah is and what's happening next.
Nine thirty-two.
Sarah is on stage, intro is done, she's speaking.
Opening Keynote is LIVE.
Planned start was nine-thirty.
We're two minutes late — within normal tolerance.
The stage timer is running, the confidence monitor on stage
shows the session title and time.
There it is — the Cue Engine.
Eight minutes out from the planned end time, it fires automatically.
That's my cue to start the pre-cue sequence:
confirm the next speaker is ready,
confirm AV is set for the handoff.
Dismiss.
Sarah is still going at ten sixteen —
she's running a minute long.
I'll nudge the cascade.
Two-minute nudge applied.
The cascade shifted everything downstream on Main Stage by two minutes.
Workshop B is unaffected — those sessions are on their own track.
Ten seventeen.
Keynote wraps.
Sarah gets a round of applause, she's been great.
Session 2 ENDED.
We're running two minutes behind planned.
The cascade has already adjusted everything —
no manual work needed.
Ten seventeen.
Session 3 goes READY.
Alex Morgan is in the wings.
Simultaneously, Workshop B Panel is starting on the parallel track.
Workshop B goes READY.
Two simultaneous sessions in pre-cue.
This is the multi-track reality: both tracks are moving at once.
I'm keeping the director view and switching between room filters.
Session 3 — Product Deep Dive —
LIVE on Main Stage at ten nineteen.
Two minutes behind planned, as expected after the keynote nudge.
Workshop B Panel LIVE.
Both tracks running.
The Programme signage board in the lobby is showing both
sessions as active — attendees in the corridor can see
exactly where to go.
It's eleven-oh-five.
Workshop B Panel has flipped to OVERRUN —
it was supposed to end at eleven hundred.
The moderator is still taking questions.
I need to make a decision:
cut it now, or let it run and cascade.
I'll let it run to eleven-ten and cascade five minutes.
Five-minute delay applied.
All subsequent Workshop B sessions have shifted —
but the Networking Lunch at thirteen hundred is an anchor.
It doesn't move.
The gap before lunch on Workshop B is now slightly tighter.
The afternoon sessions on Workshop B will need to move
briskly, but the programme is intact.
Five minutes late on Workshop B.
I'm broadcasting to the whole crew —
and to anyone on the registration role watching the session queue.
The lobby board has already updated the Workshop B times
automatically from the cascade — but
the broadcast message gives context.
People appreciate the transparency.
The afternoon runs cleanly.
The cascade absorbed the Workshop B overrun.
Lunch break at thirteen hundred on the dot — the anchor held.
The afternoon keynote went live at fifteen-fifty,
eight minutes early, wrapped on time.
One by one, sessions end.
By seventeen-ten, all ten sessions are ENDED.
The Main Stage timer has stopped.
The lobby board is showing all sessions as completed.
Tech Summit 2026 is done.
The event is over.
Let's close it out properly.
I click Generate Report.
The modal opens and the thinking animation starts —
you can see the five steps working through:
analysing session data, processing the log,
calculating metrics, drafting the summary, writing recommendations.
Summary tab first.
Four stat cards: ten sessions, ninety percent on-time rate,
plus one point eight minutes average overrun, zero incidents.
Clean day.
The executive summary from Claude reads:
'Tech Summit 2026 ran a highly efficient programme across two
tracks with minimal schedule variance.
The opening keynote ran two minutes long,
absorbed by a standard delay cascade,
and a single five-minute overrun on Workshop B was managed
without impact to the Networking Lunch anchor.
Overall execution reflects strong pre-event preparation and
responsive real-time management.' That goes directly into my client email.
Sessions tab: every session, planned versus actual, delta in minutes.
Two orange rows — the keynote nudge and
the Workshop B overrun.
Everything else is on time or within a minute.
That's a very good day.
And the recommendations.
Claude has flagged three things: consider adding a two-minute buffer
to the opening keynote slot in the next Tech Summit
iteration, confirm Workshop B moderator briefing on time management,
and review the lobby signage placement for better visibility of
the Workshop B track timing updates.
Specific.
Actionable.
Based on what actually happened today.
That was a full event on CueDeck.
We started at eight forty-five with ten PLANNED sessions and three signage displays.
We ran two parallel tracks, managed a keynote overrun,
absorbed a five-minute Workshop B cascade,
held the anchor sessions in place,
kept the crew informed with two broadcasts,
and finished with all ten sessions ENDED and
a client-ready report in three clicks.
Everything we covered in this series —
the session state machine, the roles and
team invites, the broadcast bar, the delay cascade,
the digital signage system, the AI agents,
the keyboard shortcuts, the mobile workflow,
the billing — it all came together in today's run.
This is what CueDeck is built for.
Not the setup, not the configuration — the show day.
When the clock is running and
the speakers are walking to the stage and
you need to be three moves ahead of the programme at all times.
If you've watched this series and
you're ready to run your first event —
the free plan is live at app.cuedeck.io.
Your first event costs nothing.
Sign up, load your programme, and run it.
If you've run it and you want to go deeper
— subscribe, because we're building more.
New features, new tutorials, production stories from real events.
Thanks for watching the series.
I'll see you in the next one.